SOPHIE

UX/UI DESIGNER

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a highly empathetic designer fueled by my passion to create authentic, meaningful, and inclusive experiences for people. I am personable, communicative, adaptable, and strongly believe in the importance of being a team player.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGNER & MARKETING CONSULTANT

Freelance | Atlanta, GA | May 2020 - Present

- Work collaboratively with local entrepreneurs to create the logo and visual design for their company
- Discuss and implement marketing and communication strategy to help entrepreneurs grow their brand
- Build and maintain company websites for various local businesses

STRATEGY RESEARCH CONSULTANT, FREELANCE SHM | London, UK | July 2020 - September 2020

- Provided insights from global market research to help Managing Director develop COVID-19 strategy
- Helped reimagine leadership development programming for clients' senior leadership

MARKETING COORDINATOR

Liberty Exteriors LLC | Atlanta, GA | May 2017 - August 2019

- Conducted market and competitive analysis to inform the overall Go-to-Market Strategy
- Established brand style guide and designed all print and digital marketing materials to improve CRM
- Built the company's website and Facebook page and associated assets to keep followers and clients engaged with new and original content

EDITORIAL AND MARKETING INTERN

1776 VC | Washington, DC | August 2016 - May 2017

- Developed industry reports for Managing Directors looking to grow presence in health, education, transportation, sustainability, and smart cities
- Wrote and managed content for 400+ start-ups in the 1776 network, showcasing them on the VC's website
- Assisted the Managing Director of Global Marketing to ensure all materials produced were consistent with the brand style guide
- Supported SEO optimization for corporate events, insights articles, and online content

CONTACT

706-201-6214 sophie.chen13@gmail.com sophchen.com

KEY SKILLS

- Branding & Logo Design
- Project Management
- Usability Testing
- User Research
- Visual Communication
- · Wireframing & Prototyping

PLATFORMS & TOOLS

- Adobe XD
- Balsamiq
- Canva
- Figma
- InVision
- Marvel
- Sketch
- Squarespace
- Wix
- Wordpress

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE IN UX DESIGN SPECIALIZATIONS IN UI & FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT

CareerFoundry Berlin, DE | 2020 - 2021

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION SPECIALIZATIONS MARKETING

American University
Washington, DC | 2013 - 2017